In a world where no women are locked up, the sound of music, laughter, parades, and the popping sound of popcorn will fill the streets.
So at the bottom of this image, you'll see just various people in formation sort of abstractly placed, but giving the vibe of a parade in a celebration.
Without sort of this spatial restriction, right, with just like this very like autonomy. I wanted it to feel very much like it wasn't this restrictive street. I wanted it to feel like you could be wherever you want it to be.
And so there's people hugging, embracing each other.
There's people on the megaphone, you know, shouting like excitement and like shouting for more, you know, women to not be locked up shouting for police abolition prison abolition.
People are there's someone pushing a stroller with a child in it and then there's a little sign that says, free them all sort of sitting on the stroller next to the child.
There is a young person who is holding a collection of heart blooms that is yes, placed right on the chest and the where the heart is of the larger than life, a woman who is has their hands up with excitement and joy.
That is sort of in the background, but also in a way in the foreground of the image.
And then there's also someone holding up a sign that that says, freer mothers and cash bail.
That that ensures that people know where to look to like learn more about the efforts, right.
And then there's also like two young girls with a jump rope like you know jumping rope.
And then of course there's the popcorn machine that is just like throwing the popcorn out of it and filling the large part of the poster.
This one was so fun to work on with the people's paper co-op based in Philadelphia.
And every yeah every year they do the mothers day bail out collaboration with Philadelphia bail out organization.
And the really brilliant part of the way that they get these posters is they have the artists talk with fellows in the people's paper co-op were black women who were formerly incarcerated.
And so getting the talk with them about yeah what does a world where you know mothers are free what does a world where women are no longer locked up look like well looks like you know mothers you know being reunited with with their children with their families it looks like being able to be reintegrated into into society and in doing you know the things that they.
You know want to do that bring them happiness you know but then it got you get past that and then you get to the really fun stuff of like you know it's just be really cool if like we just had a big parade.
Like so welcome the moms back and every time like they were released and you just hear like laughter and you just hear music and you just hear like popcorn like the sound of popping popcorn like from just like filling the streets and I was like that is really that I just like I felt it like a visceral like feeling of like hearing it and smelling it and like.
I was like I want that to be the main part of this poster and so yeah you see like the popcorn machine in the background and you just see the popcorn exploding and like this you know women this black woman is like just happy and just like sort of like relief like you know like there's just like this relief and joy.
And then other people like you know in this parade are also celebrating below but I just I wanted that movement and I wanted that sort of like that like celebratory vibe to this piece so yeah this was a really a really beautiful one to make and I think.
I really love creating collaborative work with with organizations and with people and so sometimes you you doesn't happen right because like it's like a tight schedule it's like a rapid response piece you just got to get it out but then times like this when you have like this opportunity to talk with people about their ideas for what freedom looks like or what a world without prisons looks like I think is so if that's like the juicy conversations and that's where like you really get to this.
So in this way it's like this is a really good thing to see this kind of things to these visions of again thinking beyond what's in front of us thinking beyond just like oh it just looks like it just looks like this prison no longer here it's like okay but then what right what does that look like and what what are we.
us in like, why do we want those prisons gone? Why do we want abolition? Right? Because we want
people to thrive and we want people to like be able to live in their joy free of fear. And so
yeah, this is yeah, one of my favorite pieces.